foreign
[Music]
change is the next leg of transformation
its definitive Relentless and requires a
holistic and human-centric approach a
reimagined approach to transformation
has become a fundamental step in
orchestrating expansion and development
in any organization transformation
realized powered by evi is a brand new
chapter where we bring to inspiring
stories of business transformation that
have put the customer and Innovation at
the core the last episode of the series
takes us through the transformation
journey of the largest private sector
non-life insurer in India
businesses of today can stand the test
of time only by adapting to change
leaders are leveraging the emerging
trends of Savvy consumers evolving go to
market channels and the power of
technology to achieve scale and
long-term growth now this week on the
six part series of transformation
realized powered by ebi we bring to you
the story of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance India's largest private sector
long life insurer and its acquisition of
bharti aksar General a strategic move
driven by ambition and vision not only
that this acquisition Heralds a new era
of power and dominance to talk to us
more about this please welcome bhagavdas
Gupta who is the MD and CEO of ICICI
Lombard and Rohan sachdev who is the
Consulting Services leader at Eva India
Mr Das Gupta Mr sachday both of you
thank you for your time here on CNBC TV
18 and for being with us here on this
special episode I'll start with you
because you know being the largest
private sector non life insurance not an
easy task running a company like that
give us an insight into how you've run
the company over these years to ensure
that it maintains that pole position
that it has achieved now over the years
so Ritu maybe I can start on a lighter
vein I guess we should thank our
competitors for being so generous with
us
um and which is why we we are where we
are but on a serious note I think there
are a few foundational pillars that we
focused on as a company
um the number one absolute number one
has been building consumer Trust
Insurance is a business of uh in a sense
a delayed gratification of a promise to
peer claim if something happens at a
later point in time right so how you
service that experience for customers is
vital in terms of building uh you know a
brand in a franchise so that's
Foundation number one number two you
know leadership for what I mean
leadership not just from a top line
perspective but it has to be more
sustainable yeah so focus on risk
management focus on all other aspects of
business rather than just Top Line I
think that's that's important third
thing is that we believe we've tried to
stay invested and you know kind of
invested ahead of the time on uh Tech
you know and this is not just now over
the years we've always been focused on
declare Innovation yeah and that's
helped us and underpinning all of this
is I think a usual issue of people and
culture uh you know honestly speaking I
think we are very fortunate to have the
team that we do a great bunch of guys
a lot of ownership a lot of
Entrepreneurship and a sense of pride in
whatever they have jointly created so
yes uh you know I started with the joke
about the competition I think really the
team doesn't like to be behind uh you
know anyone and that's a that's a DNA
that's very important
but you know how
bharti Acts
fit in the overall scheme of things
so if you look at the timing
um you know this was just after the
pandemic uh all of us got you know
locked down there was Panic All Around
um and after a couple of months of the
lockdown we started thinking that this
was probably a good time to think about
you know organic growth simply because
uh at least our belief is well yeah you
know it's also the time that when you
know people are more afraid that's the
time to think about growth insurance and
so we started looking at opportunities
and uh and when you look at a specific
Target uh bharti AXA was really a very
uh apt Target for us in terms of size it
was roughly about 22 percent of our size
uh it was doing well it was you know
scaling up but it was still relatively
subscale ah so if you look at its
business numbers uh we measure our
business and combined ratio so combined
ratio was a bit elevated but if you
split that uh roughly 78 was loss and 42
percent was the expense ratio in a total
combined of 120 yeah which basically
showed you that the business was
underlying business was fine it was just
that it was upscale so expenses were
very elevated thirdly there were certain
uh distribution Partnerships that they
had which was adding to our overall
franchise
and lastly and to me this is very
important uh we liked the the culture
and the team because at the end of the
day those soft aspects play a very
important role and you know we were
doing this virtually yeah you know or
everything that we did from diligence
diligence negotiation you know till the
day that we got the final approval yeah
there was no physical meeting between
the teams oh wow it was all virtual so
you had to trust uh you know the team
and the and the management there and the
promoters but Mrs Sasha was that the
most unique aspect of this deal I mean
the entire deal being stitched together
virtually or what do you think how is
this any different from the several
other Acquisitions you've helped
undertake see I think I think first of
all let's understand yeah of course
being in covert it was unique right from
the propositioning to the end of the
deal I met the most of the icsa number
team for the first time well I met them
at the party physically for the first
time the celebrity party so everything
was at the end of the draft at the end
of the transaction and three months
after that uh so everything was done
virtually but just stepping back to when
people think about this sort of DLC
globally a lot of deals happen in
insurance
I think what people uh underestimate is
people often look at financial services
from a balance sheet size perspective
but you look at the volume of
transactions that go through in India is
of a totally different genre yeah so
when you had something like a bharti AXA
and icslumber coming together it's the
probably the largest deal in the
insurance World in India that's ever
happened so far so I think that was one
thing that was sort of I would say very
unique about this deal uh it was large
just another tell you scale think about
it they were 16
000 Distributors that we needed to bring
on together
they were 3400 employees that were in
absolutely and bhargav's agenda was
always to observe them absorb them in a
very gentle manner and you know bring
them in as a family rather than sort of
make them feel that they're new in the
environment I think that was the second
one you just think about we had about
three crore sort of uh customer letters
to send out they were 140 branches of
bharti that we had to uh think about on
top of that the product portfolios were
very different uh the technology systems
were different they had a different data
system we had a different data system
all of that so as you put it all
together uh I would probably say and I
had worked on a lot of global insurance
deals uh historically I would say this
was done uh in a pretty rapid manner in
a very very transparent Manner and I
think you've also got to think about we
are a very regulated industry yeah so at
all times are being transferred to
regulated
I leave there for biograph to answer but
but so you know all in all um it was and
as you said was done in Kobe
so building relationships with people on
both sides building trust then
delivering at speed all of us then that
was done in a virtual environment so
yeah I'd say it was pretty unique in
that sense all right uh hold your
thoughts because we have to take a very
short break uh we're back in just a
moment stay with us
[Music]
foreign
episode of transformation realized
powered by ey where today we're talking
to the top leadership at ICICI Lombard
as well as Rohan sashley from Evie Mr
paragraph that's Gupta Andrew thank you
for staying on uh you know this is not
an easy deal we've been talking about
the size of the deal and Rohan has
outlined how unique it was uh what would
you say with some of the top three
challenges if you were you know to
outline uh when you looked at the deals
and how were you able to smooth things
over to achieve closure in uh you know
in the time that you wanted
um I would say maybe there are three key
aspects that we were particularly
focused on uh which we felt with the uh
the three challenges that we had to
address uh very very tightly
first was as we both said this was done
in a virtual environment
ah where the country was going through
infrequent lockdowns closures uh offices
would be closed suddenly uh courts you
know at times were not open but we have
a very tight time frame to execute so we
had given ourselves roughly about 12
months to complete the entire
transaction from deal announcement to uh
legal tier one uh and we did not want to
sleep on that timeline so execution at
speed in a context of uncertainty
because of covet and you know
unpredictable lockdowns etcetera I think
that was uh probably challenge number
one
secondly once we got the ld1 done
the integration effort that we put in
together thereafter
I think the key objective for us was
that you know we were bringing two
organizations together and our
philosophy was one plus one cannot be
two it has to be much more so we did not
want to lose momentum on core business
so we have to ensure the core business
you know carried on you know as BAU
while we get this integration done at
the pace that we set for ourselves so we
didn't want the core business to get
distracted in the either of the
organizations
and thirdly and Rohan rightly pointed
this out you know we're in a Services
business and you know when you look at
an acquisition what is it that you're
getting as a value right uh you would
argue that value can be balance sheet
could be customers could be
policyholders could be Distributors but
finally all of that boils down to the
team and the people and you had to
protect the team and give them a sense
of you know comfort and confidence that
you're coming in and you are not you
know there is no winner or loser here we
are coming together as two teams yeah
and uh you know obviously in the part of
the integration process the best man
will win but it will not be driven by
which organization you are coming from
it is purely based on Merit I think
those three were the key uh you know
challenges that we focused on
and hence uh you know having the right
delivery architecture uh you know we
work with Rohan stream in eny we also
had a HR you know firm which was helping
us on the people and culture side I
think getting everyone together to work
as one team was the most important uh
people management and the inter project
management overall you know now that
you've outlined the challenges tell us
what synergies you've seen since the
merger took effect and you know what is
the sort of sustainable advantage that
you see in the long term uh from the two
entities coming together
so you started by saying that we were
number one in in the private sector
right so we've been number one in the
private sector for 20 years but we were
number five in aggregate there are four
companies which were the Legacy
companies which were ahead of us yeah
this transaction leaped from us to a
second position in the overall industry
so gave us a market standing Improvement
which would have maybe taken us two to
three as extra time if you hadn't done
this transaction
secondly if you look at the transaction
as I said this was roughly about 20 to
23 percent of our size we paid about
seven point three percent of our stock
to do this transaction so there was a
significant value to be uh you know
delivered if you could get this energy
Synergy benefits that we talked about
and uh you know when two organizations
come in in the same line of business in
a sense there are obviously a lot of
scope for Synergy and you know whatever
we estimated as an organization in terms
of synergy uh the number that we put out
in the market was 200 crores uh we got
the Synergy benefits sooner uh you know
before time
and we got higher level of synergy
benefit that we did not
completely factor in because you
couldn't Factor everything so for
example you look at the Synergy on
productivity on people cost on
technology stack on branches
those are factored in right but there
are certain things that we saw in claims
practices where maybe in the same uh you
know partner maybe in a hospital or a
garage we saw slight differences between
what we were doing and versus what they
were doing now it was not always that we
were always better than you know they
were else they were in every part of the
you know chain so there were a lot of
learnings from each other that we we
initially hadn't anticipated okay plus I
think they were very disciplined about
the reserving and their accounting uh
which was expected but we couldn't
account for it you know or anticipated
you know fully which has been an
additional benefit well you know it's
essentially what would you say has been
has been approached to this transaction
I mean uh there were things that were
factored in that were probably on the
positive side I don't know if there were
some on the negative side but day one
Readiness getting their synergies
getting everything on board what was
your approach to it so I think uh just
in the background we actually worked
with bhargav our transactions team
worked with bhargav in actually making
the marriage happen initially between
ICC and uh yeah so we had some
background in terms of that and then we
came to the post-motor integration to
look at what we could do I think I would
say three or four things first of all
you know we asked the right question to
start with and we asked bharga really
what do you want to achieve out of this
and I think I still remember his words
he was very clear see I want a very
smooth time-bound regulatory transparent
and beneficial to all a deal to happen
and that's what I expect from the post
merger integration so I think when the
leadership is very clear from both sides
and what they're going to run after what
they want to achieve I think that was
one great sort of stepping stone I think
secondly I think we drew up a joint
scorecard and I think that was pretty
good for us that our joint our
scorecards were the same absolutely same
what for these scorecards this was all
about whether we can get the synergistic
value whether we can take cost out can
we get additional Revenue how do we
settle the people in how do we look at a
new joint business so how well you're
doing on a scale of say one to ten on
those parameters well I think I think we
did pretty well uh and that is uh
reflective on how bhagava sort of uh uh
sort of uh rewarded us and sort of where
we've seen the business go today
but I think what that actually meant
ritual is you have a very clear
scorecard second part of it was putting
the right team in place these
Integrations are far more complex that
are visible to the eye
they're very complex and every aspect
has to be taken care of yeah you know
bhagava made an example of claim
settlement are they doing it better in
one area are we doing it better in one
area which is the one practice we choose
and I think bharga was very clear choose
the best practice Yeah so the second not
just what we are doing is right just
let's choose what is best for our
customers our shareholders
so that was there I think so we put the
team together
and we actually had a unique team we had
a bunch of Industry Specialists we had
practitioners and then from our
Consulting business in ey and then we
have ey Parthenon which specializes in
postmodger integration so we got a
postmodger integration office as a layer
on top to govern the entire project and
that governance was not only for ey it
was governing a joint team from icsa
Lombard and ey so that was one joint
team we used to have a call every
morning with 60 people on it every
morning every day every single day 90
people across iciciency every day every
single day we used to call it gopal's
call because he used to run the call RCF
was used but we used to do it every
morning yeah so that was the second part
I think the third part was being very
clear in terms of what are going to be
the benefits at which point of time
bharga was always very very clear about
the cultural Equalization
that we had to create in the new
organization and how we treated people
who are coming in so that was a big
aspect of what we did then looking at
technology
and looking at all the regulatory
approvals what are the approvals we will
need at what PowerPoint will they come
if there is a delay will we stop our
work or what will we do how will we deal
with that delay and if there's a delay
what's the catch-up mechanism
so and then you know you have various
streams how do they integrate to get the
value out uh that is there I I would say
technology was a very very big part I
think people might undermine that but
when you're doing such a big merger
imagine just you know merging a general
ledger the amount of thinking we have to
do how do we bring it together all right
uh hold your thoughts because we have to
take a very short break uh we're back in
just a moment stay with us
[Music]
welcome back you're watching
transformation realized powered by ey
we're in conversation with Mr bhagavdas
Gupta and Mr Rohan sashdev thank you
gentlemen for staying on uh and Mr Das
Gupta again let me start with you uh now
that this Mega integration that we spoke
about is finally behind you uh what's
next for ICICI Lombard what's your
vision for the next three to five years
I'm not asking if you're looking at
another inorganic opportunity but what
is the larger uh you know sort of vision
because when we talk about insurance in
India severely under penetrated even two
days so you know what can the company do
so as the famous ad line said we are
number two so we try harder so as I said
we are still number two so there's still
a long way for us to go uh I think what
uh what we're looking at is
a company we are extremely optimistic
about our sector
um and uh obviously underpinned by
what's happening in the underlying
economy I mean if economy grows at
let's hope seven percent and eight
percent not six percent uh you're
talking about a insurance growth of
roughly two and a half times so between
18 to 20 percent yeah ah our aspiration
will continue to be that we grow faster
than the market in a sustainable manner
I mean that's core as I said right in
the beginning
um now the changes that we are seeing
since we touched upon some of the the
regulatory processes involved uh the
changes that we are seeing in regulation
are very very positive from our sector
perspective clearly the current
regulator is very keen to uh increase
ease of doing Insurance business and
drive penetration faster now the changes
that are being brought about we believe
can give it another few percentage Point
Philip so you are looking at let's say
as a sector potentially growing at about
20 plus
now within that one of the key roles
that insurance places risk transfer and
by
providing that security support it
encourages entrepreneurship but our
sense is the role of insurance gradually
is Shifting away from risk transfer to
risk management and that's a journey
that we are on apart from business
growth and you know overall Market
positioning that of course is an
aspiration for us I think the bigger
opportunity for us is to transform what
we the services that we provide to
customers and again there's a lot of
talk about the insurance act changes
which will facilitate some of these
things so I think the exciting times for
insurance uh both in terms of market
growth as also the transformative power
that some of the regulatory changes are
potentially unleashing will be exciting
okay you know before we close this
episode since we're talking about the
transformation itself uh your final
thoughts on you know what are some of
the key learnings to the industry to
take away when working on an integration
of this size uh you know what what would
your suggestions or advice or learning
the takeaways be
I think uh I would just you know three
or four things uh mainly I think one is
uh I think Clarity of thought on why
you're doing this I think bhagavat
articulated that they'd seen what was
sitting in the AXA business and how
could they sort of in lots of ways
energize that so I think just the
clarity of thought in terms of uh how
you're gonna do this and why you're
going to do this second one is I think
uh think about people one big part of an
integration of this size and in a
financial services business there's a
lot of people involved is about the
cultural fitment and how are you going
to make that happen even if it's not
there on day one
what's your plan in place to get that to
happen your work doesn't stop when the
Merlin correctly you know you've got to
have those uh in this example you've got
to have those uh 3 000 people living and
breathing icsa Lombard yeah so I think
how do you think about that how do you
welcome them I think that's very
important because that could be
disruptive otherwise I think third one I
would say is terms of you know uh
transparency uh to all the stakeholders
transparency to the regulators and
transparency to the teams that are
working on this
uh fourth I would say is just putting
together the right structure
and that vision
saying you know if you're going to go
through this 18-month Journey what do we
want to achieve at the end of the 18
month and how do we measure ourselves uh
uh in a fair manner
I think we never measured ourselves
saying
uh you're gonna play me this have you
I've this I've done this I've done we
measured thing have we achieved at least
90 of what we set out to achieve and
what is there that is left and what do
we need to do differently to achieve
that uh I would say is that so I would
say these are the four or five things
that uh people should uh people should
think about I would also say to end with
this uh it
they are difficult but I think if you
put a structure around it they're
actually quite a fun Journey because
every day there's new excitement around
these and I think that's really great so
for our teams they went away from this
assignment learning a lot
learning a lot and every single one of
them is super proud of what they
achieved uh really and that I think so
just uh those things will be very
important as you look at a large those
are wonderful things to hear and uh to
focus on the structure have transparency
with all of the stakeholders involved
take the teams together and of course
the work doesn't stop with the
integration to continue to build that
culture with the employees that you
brought together on that note uh
gentlemen thank you very much for
sharing your thoughts and for sharing
your story with us here on CNBC tv18 it
was a pleasure speaking to both of you
thank you thank you thank you thank you
on that note we're going to wrap up this
special series of transformation
realized powered by ey thank you for
watching and it's a goodbye from all of
us
that's it then on this show today
throughout the series businesses have
come to recognize the critical
significance of transformation in
today's world as the series concludes it
leaves a lasting message that embracing
change and adaptation is essential for
Success the journey may be over but the
impact of realization will shape the
future of businesses around the world
from all of us here goodbye thanks for
watching
thank you
Focus
ideate innovate enable